# ESMÉ JAMES

• gameplay programmer •

• Number 438-874-5690 • +33 6 16 50 78 80 • Email <u>esmealicejames@gmail.com</u>

• Portfolio <u>ezyjay.github.io</u>

• YouTube Esmé James Makes Games

• LinkedIn <u>linkedin.com/in/esmealicejames</u>

• Github github.com/ezyjay

## ABOUT ME

After graduating from UQAC with a masters in programming (specializing in Video Games), I moved to Montréal where I have been working as a gameplay programmer since 2018. During this time I have worked on Spiritfarer (+DLCs) and an unannounced upcoming project.

#### EDUCATION

2017 - 2018 • UQAC

Masters in computer science/video games

2013 - 2018 • ISEN (Engineering school in Brest, France)

Masters in engineering/computer science

### EXPERIENCE

2018 - Present Thunder Lotus Games

2021 - Present: Gameplay/Tools Programmer on Unannounced project

2018 - 2021: Gameplay Programmer on Spiritfarer (+ DLCs)

- A 2D narrative/management game around the theme of death
- Unity 3D, C#, Perforce
- Coding and design of gameplay and UI systems (building system, minigames, interactions, in-game menus)
  - Profiling and optimizing code
  - Voluntary participation at PAX East in the Spiritfarer booth

## PERSONAL PROJECTS

2021 <u>Tiny Castles: A sandcastle building simulation</u>

6-month project made with Unity 3D, C# and Clayxels

- Grid-based block building with Undo/Redo capabilities
- Small UI for shape selection and mode changes
- Creation of 3D assets with Clayxels (in engine asset creator)

2020 <u>Underwater Octopus puzzle game</u>

2-month project made with Unity 3D, C#

- Puzzle design
- Creation of 3D assets with Blender

#### SKILLS

Unity 3D, C#

Perforce

Blender

Unreal Engine, C++

#### HOBBIES

Drawing/Illustration

**Photography** 

Music Production, Guitar & Saxophone

Wall climbing & Running

Video games & Cinema